Part 4 weight loss interventions.
5% loss in body weight.
What happens if these supportive measures
are unsuccessful?
If there is a 5% drop in body weight,
you will be switched
to a complete liquid diet.
This means that instead
of consuming calories through solid foods,
all calories will come from liquids
which are easier to swallow.
You will consume
bottles filled with liquids
that are complete
in all the nutrients and calories needed.
Our dietitian will provide you
with these bottles
and tell you how many bottles
to consume per day.
Although this may not sound appetizing,
the benefits of a liquid diet
are ease of counting calories
and the ease of swallowing.
You will not have to put
enormous amounts of effort into chewing
and swallowing food, while your doctor
and their team can make sure
that you are receiving all the nutrition
and calories needed throughout treatment.
10% loss in body weight.
If there is a 10% or more loss of body
weight,
a feeding tube will be inserted.
A feeding tube
allows you to intake nourishment directly
by bypassing the need to chew and swallow
food.
A feeding tube is an invasive intervention
that we want to avoid due
to difficulty with insertion,
the need to maintain it,
and a greater risk
for irritation and infection.